

PROJECTS

ROCKET BATTLE

A two player battle-ship style game. Destroy your opponents' rockets before they destroy yours. This project uses JS, JQuery, and the Space X API to return selected data that shows the user when they have hit a specific rocket. This project was created utilizing mob programming.

BREAKING DOWN THE BAD

An informational soundboard generator that plays 3 randomly selected audio files for each character in the Breaking Bad TV series. This app also contains fun facts about the show, and its characters. This project uses JS, JQuery, React, Firebase, and the Breaking Bad API.

TRIVIA TV

Do you know your TV facts? This app generates 10 randomly selected questions from the Trivia API, and the questions are based off the TV/Entertainment genre. The languages used consists of Sass, JavaScript, JQuery, and Rest API working in a paired programming.



ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

JUNO COLLEGE OF TECHNOLOGY

FEB 2020 - MAY 2020

Bootcamp Cohort #26 | Web Development Part-Time Web Development Course Part-Time JavaScript Course

HUMBER COLLEGE

SEPT 2012 - APR 2015

Architectural Technology Advanced Diploma with Honours and work placement

MIGUEL CABRERA

FRONT FND DEVELOPER

migueledward@hotmail.com • (647) 216-0131

mcabrera.ca 💟 in 💭







PROFILE

I am a Front End Web Developer with a positive attitude, open mindset, and a passion for building and designing. With previous experience in the tech field, I have learned to thrive under high pressure environments with firm deadlines. I also gained familiarity with working on mobile apps and creating 3D and Virtual Reality content to populate an app in response to client requests. I look forward to opportunities where I can work with a team, and collaborate ideas to create responsive, and accessible web designs.

TECH SKILLS

- HTMI 5
- CSS3
- Sass
- JavaScript
- ¡Query
- Firebase
- Terminal
- React
- Rest API
- Git
- GitHub
- Slack
- UX & UI
- · Visual Studio Code
- Responsive Design
- Web Accessibility
- Paired/Mob Programming
- Remote Collaboration

WORK EXPERIENCE

SCREENING OFFICER

GardaWorld, 2017-Present

- Supervised international security checkpoint
- Assisted customers and resolved all gueries related to travel
- Operated detecting devices to screen individuals and prevent passage of prohibited articles into restricted areas

CONTENT CREATION SPECIALIST

KiSP Inc. 2014-2017 & Yulio Technologies, 2016-2017

- Created conceptual buildings/environments using SketchUp/Revit
- Debugged projects for errors prior to final release for company Mobile App
- Rendered photo-realistic images to create Virtual Reality Scenes
- Created net new content for Mobile App KITS Collaborator, using AutoCAD, SketchUp and Revit.
- Edited pre-configured DWG files according to client requests within the app
- Produced renderings of furniture sets from client catalogues